Galarc Kingdom, Amande Market Town
I'll send a messenger
to you tomorrow morning.
Thank you for conveying me all the way here.
Allow me to show you to your
lodgings, Master Haruto.
Thank you.
Spirit Chronicles 2
I'm not averse to striking
someone down for discourtesy.
Why, you...
You little...
Intruders
Haruto!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Cecilia.
Is everything all right? You're not hurt?
I'm not injured anywhere.
Please, don't worry.
We seem to be attracting attention
from everyone in this restaurant.
What?
And so, Miss Liselotte has
arranged a place for us to stay.
We'll be sojourning here in
Amande for the next few days.
All right.
I'm sorry to tell you this only
after everything's been decided.
That's all right. What about Aria?
As Cecilia, you give off a much different
impression, so I think we'll be all right.
More worrying is...
There were nobles associated
with the Beltrum Kingdom's
royal family traveling with them.
What? Who?
Her Highness the second princess,
Flora, as well as Duke Huguenot,
and Miss Roanna, from the
ducal house of Fontaine.
They're all quite important people.
Princess Flora and Miss Roanna
know you very well, don't they?
They didn't notice?
Princess Flora's instincts are sharp.
She seems to have sensed something is odd.
But I've changed my hair color,
so I'm sure we'll be all right.
Maybe it would be better for
us to leave Amande after all.
No. There is some risk in staying,
but I want to establish a good
rapport with Miss Liselotte.
With Miss Liselotte?
If the Hero of the Kingdom of Galarc
is someone I've been looking for,
then establishing a rapport with someone
who has authority in this country
is for the best.
All right. But don't let your guard down.
Miss Liselotte is famous for
being shrewd and capable.
Right.
If there's anything I can do, just tell me!
Thank you. Actually, there is something.
What is it?
The thing is, I'm meant to
visit Miss Liselotte tomorrow.
If you wouldn't mind,
would you teach me the proper manners
for visiting a noble's house?
Leave it to me!
Still, Liselotte, that attendant
of yours... Aria, was it?
Her work is truly outstanding.
Thank you.
But the Hero would have had the power
to overturn that situation, wouldn't he?
Possibly. Unfortunately, he is
lacking in practical experience.
Still, he had the strength to
lift the minotaur's greatsword.
Would it be right to think that that
strength came from his Divine Arms?
That is very likely.
As with enchanted swords, a person must have
an affinity for Divine Arms to use their power.
But it is said that the affinity for
Divine Arms rests solely with Heroes.
That he could draw on that
power to such an extent
with no training leaves
us with many questions.
Then, practical experience is the
only thing he is missing after all.
The Hero is important. I do not relish
the thought of sending him into danger.
It would be premature to send him into
battle simply to gain experience,
so I have had him fighting
mock battles with the knights.
His first experience with battle
ended up being quite a dire one.
We'll turn it into a positive by remembering
that he's gained valuable experience.
As I thought, the duke
isn't looking for the Hero
to be more than a symbol of power right now.
In the end...
if that person hadn't shown up, it's possible
that all of us would have been slaughtered.
You're speaking of Master Haruto.
He slew three minotaurs
in the blink of an eye.
That simply isn't possible unless one can
manipulate an enchanted sword at will.
And the true identity of an enchanted
swordsman of this caliber...
Liselotte, what do you think?
His skill with a sword,
as well as all of his words and actions,
speak of refinement and education.
He may be hiding his identity,
or he may be from a fallen noble house.
I'd like to know a little
more about him
before building a future relationship.
Would you like to attend my
meeting with him tomorrow?
It's a great help that you
comprehend things so quickly.
I understand.
It wouldn't do to call it thanks,
but please make use of my knights.
Your knights, Your Grace?
You intend to investigate the cause
of the monster spawnings, don't you?
When exploring the forest, having more
personnel available will never go amiss.
That would be a great help. Thank you.
Well, we continue to be faced
with unusual situations.
Yes. Not long ago,
we began receiving reports
that the number of adventurer
disappearances had been increasing.
It was over here, wasn't it?
Indeed.
Are you really going to
take us to that restaurant?
It's famous for having incredibly
high prices, you know?
There's no need to worry about money.
We've been there before.
Don't you know who we are?
You're nobles!
I'm in a very good mood!
What about you, Stewart?
Yes, Alphonse. And this has washed
away the events of this afternoon.
Don't talk about that!
That Haruto or whatever his name is...
swooping in from nowhere like that.
Who does he think he is?
More than that, what about that Hero?
You two. In that battle earlier, you freaked
out and hid in the back, didn't you?
Your legs totally gave out on you.
You'd better get your acts together,
O honorable knights.
It wasn't our legs that gave out in fear!
He treats us as though we're
insignificant weaklings!
Stop talking about him!
Now I need another drink!
We can't use it?
I'm talking about the room
with a view of the garden!
Yes. Some other customers
are already using that room.
Any other room would be ready immediately.
Just have those other customers switch rooms.
If it's about money, I'll pay you triple.
I'm very sorry.
And this silly girl had
fallen asleep in the bath!
I went in later and got such a shock.
It's so cozy and feels so good.
Maybe we should try to
keep the sleeping to beds.
You're in my way! Move!
Please don't do this, sir.
You're not worth talking to. Don't blame
me for whatever happens to you later!
What happens to me does not matter.
Is someone fighting?
This guy just doesn't listen to money.
Enough, Stewart. We'll just talk
to these other customers ourselves.
Please, stop.
My deepest apologies, sir.
May I ask you for an explanation?
You're... Haruto or something, aren't you?
I'm very sorry. May I ask who you are?
Oh, my apologies.
I am Stewart Huguenot.
This is Alphonse Rodan.
We are knights affiliated with
the group that you rescued today.
Stewart? Alphonse?
I see. I apologize for not recognizing you.
Now, what brings you here?
We want to use this room, you see.
I see. We were just finishing our meal.
Please, come in, if you'd like.
Come over here, both of you.
Now, now.
Stop right there.
What is it?
You two. Since you're here,
why don't you stay and dine with us?
Unfortunately, we've already
had our fill of food and drink.
What's this? You're refusing our invitation?
We are also tired from our journey.
I can't say I'm impressed.
You may be good with a sword,
but you're a commoner, aren't you?
I beg that you pardon us.
Alphonse, we should probably...
Sir, if you continue to
trouble other patrons,
we will have to take appropriate measures.
We'll go, then.
Stop.
A-Alphonse?
What is it?
It appears that you don't know the
proper way to interact with nobility.
Unfortunately, I was born a commoner.
I'm not averse to striking
someone down for discourtesy.
I've heard that national and regional
laws place limits on discourtesy kills.
Have I committed some discourtesy which
would be applicable under such laws?
Why, you...
Who do you think you are, you scum?!
You little...
Alphonse!
Let him go, you vermin!
If I let him go, it's likely
he'll try to hit me again.
Stop playing around!
What you've done is unforgivable!
You little...
It doesn't seem we'll be able to
settle this peaceably anymore.
Could I trouble you
to bring someone who might be able to
deal with them as is appropriate?
Spirit Chronicles 2
Those are the particulars of the situation.
Testimony from the staff
corroborates the information.
I see.
This couldn't be worse!
I didn't want him to think
that nobles are arrogant,
but given an incident like this,
he's sure to be more wary!
Those arrogant fools.
Where is Master Haruto?
He has returned to the inn to rest.
Then I'll go and apologize
to him tomorrow morning.
Understood. I will make the
appropriate preparations.
As a parent, I will settle those
ignorant fools' misconduct personally.
Might I ask you to convey my
apologies and sincerity to him?
Of course, Your Grace.
Little fools.
I didn't expect much from you,
but this incident has made me despair
from the depths of my heart.
I told you not to expect a second chance.
Rejoice! I shall disinherit you,
just as you wished.
D-Disinherit?!
That's going too far!
It was just a quarrel with
some commoner swordsman.
Just a commoner?
He appears to be far more
competent than you are.
Though your great lack of
ability is also a factor.
What did you say?
You may be a duke, Your Grace,
but I must ask that you take back those words!
That swordsman handled three minotaurs
as if they were merely playthings.
Can you do the same?
If I had an enchanted sword, then I...
I heard that the two of you attacked him
together, and he turned the tables on you.
Well, I will grant you an
opportunity to clear your name.
After all, I'm certain you would have
difficulty facing your father as things stand.
I'll do it! Please give me a chance!
Liselotte will be investigating
the forest to the west of Amande.
And you want me to help her.
Should you distinguish yourself
somehow as part of the advance party,
then I wouldn't mind putting in a good
word for you as regards this matter.
Of course, should you
fail to produce results,
I will ask that you return to
Rodania and remain confined there.
Please, allow me to take this opportunity!
Very well. However...
only on the condition that you
apologize to Master Haruto first.
Do you understand?
Y-Yes.
Yes, Your Grace.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
Because I asked you to accompany me,
I subjected you to even more worry.
It's all right, though my heart
is still racing a little.
Then, Cecilia, would you like to stay in
the stone house with Aishia starting today?
I couldn't! It's all right.
Everything is fine.
But it's difficult for you
to feel at ease, isn't it?
It's all right. Besides, I don't
want to leave your side, Haruto.
Oh! Out of concern!
I'm just concerned about you!
Yes. Thank you.
If the time comes, we can just run away.
Th-That's right!
Stay here and stand by.
Yes, my lady.
My name is Cecilia.
I'm Aishia.
I'm pleased to meet you.
Both of you are very beautiful.
Thank you.
Would the two of you mind
waiting in the other room?
All right.
If you'll excuse us.
Duke Huguenot wishes to apologize
to you, Master Haruto.
I see.
If you have any requests, he asks that
you make them, whatever they may be.
Then, may I ask that testimony that
the dispute was settled amicably
be put into writing?
Of course.
I will act as an arbitrator and
have such a document created.
Thank you.
And, if you have no objections, I will
invite you to my home as planned.
Would you like to come for lunch?
Your two companions are welcome, too.
I'm very sorry. They seem to still be
tired from the events of last night.
I will call on you alone.
What do you think?
I feel it favors me too heavily.
If you have no objections
to it, Your Grace, then...
It's only natural that I do this.
Then we'll leave drawing up the official
contract to our third party, Liselotte.
Of course, Your Grace.
Now, as a parent... I would like to take
responsibility and atone for this crime.
Would you be willing to grant them
an opportunity to apologize to you?
Yes, I wouldn't mind.
Thank you.
Come in!
Now, be grateful that he is so magnanimous.
Apologize properly.
We are very sorry!
Please raise your heads.
Oh! Master Haruto!
I am honored to see you a
second time, Princess Flora.
Well, have a seat. Seems like
you've had it pretty rough.
Not at all. If you'll permit me.
I'd expect nothing less.
The chef here at Liselotte's
mansion has impressive skills.
I'm honored you think so.
But when I eat good meat,
it does make me crave rice.
Actually, we tried to prepare
this rice you speak of...
You did?
But it seems to be slightly different
from the rice of your world, Sir Hiroaki.
We tried boiling it as it was, but the
taste wasn't particularly pleasing.
So we made some adjustments.
Well... Let's see now.
This is...
This is good! Cheese risotto, huh?
I'm honored you feel that way.
You're aware of this dish, then, Sir Hiroaki?
Oh, it's the name of a dish from my
world that's a lot like this one.
If that's the case, then I will take this
opportunity to name this dish "risotto."
Sure. That's fine with me.
It's delicious!
It's so rich from all the cheese.
This isn't bad at all.
There's this and also the pasta that
the Ricca Company developed.
She must have knowledge from Earth.
How do you like it, Master Haruto?
It's wonderful!
I never imagined that rice
could be made edible.
Master Haruto, how old were you
when you began your journey?
I was eleven years old.
Speaking of which, how old are you now?
I am sixteen now.
And you've been traveling
since you were a kid?
I guess if you were with your parents,
it wouldn't be impossible.
Both of my parents died before
I set out on my journey.
In general, I've traveled alone.
I see.
I'm sorry to make you speak of it.
It's all right. Please,
don't let it bother you.
Um, Master Haruto, why did you decide
to set out on a journey alone?
I think it was because
I was searching for someone with a
certain connection to my parents.
Do you have any intention of
settling somewhere permanently?
I am still in the midst of my journey.
In that case, I do hope you'll consider
the Kingdom of Beltrum for a
future permanent residence.
I would be willing to grant very favorable
terms to a swordsman of your caliber.
Oh, my! In that case, I would like to
submit my name for consideration as well.
I am most grateful. If the fates allow.
Look at everyone fawning over you!
Is this the birth of a new hero?
I would never presume!
Someone like me could never measure up
to a real Hero like you, Sir Hiroaki!
Well, no matter how much good you may do,
there's a certain status and strength
that only a real Hero possesses.
But if you understand that, then you might
end up going farther than anyone thinks.
I am honored you think so.
Which reminds me... I've heard rumors
that a Hero has arrived in the
Kingdom of Galarc as well.
Given such a conspicuous pillar,
it would be impossible to hide it.
The Hero is supposed to be officially
presented at the soirée, right?
Galarc's Lady Hero or whatever.
The Hero is a woman?
Yes, Dame Sumeragi Satsuki.
She is the Hero who was
summoned to our kingdom.
Sumeragi Satsuki?
Satsuki-san and Takahisa-kun vanished first.
Do you think they came to this world?
There's no mistake. She's one of the
people Miharu-san is searching for.
Sir Hiroaki will also be
presented at that party.
The Hero of the Kingdom of Beltrum,
Sir Shigekura Rui, has also been invited.
It's annoying to be treated
like an object to be shown off,
but this is one of the duties of a Hero, too.
It sounds like it there will be
many important personages there.
There may be one more.
It's rumored that the Hero summoned
to the Centostella Kingdom may attend.
I see.
This finally gets us one step closer.
That's incredible progress.
This means I'll have good news
for Miharu-san and the others!
Blast it! Why am I forced to do this...
because of that riffraff?
I am not talentless.
You rotten duke, you just watch!
I'll show you!
Stay alert!
We may encounter another
minotaur at any time!
No need for that.
There aren't any monsters
left in the forest, you see?
Who are you?
Next Time
The Clutches of Evil, Stealing Ever Closer
"The Clutches of Evil, Stealing Ever Closer."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Illustration: Minazuki Futago